Remember the cute puppy from the previous lesson?
还记得第一节课的可爱小狗吗？
He set the stage as an agent who learns from trial
我们用它来比喻智能体 智能体通过试错
and error how to behave in an environment to maximize reward.
学习如何在环境中完成各种动作并最大化奖励
But what do we mean when we talk about reinforcement learning in general?
但是通常强化学习到底是什么意思呢？
Well, you might be surprised to hear
你可能会惊讶地发现
that not much changes when we trade this puppy for a self-driving car,
当我们将小狗替换成无人驾驶汽车
a robot, or a more in general, reinforcement learning agent.
机器人或一般的强化学习智能体时 没有什么太大的变化
In particular, the RL framework is characterized
尤其是 RL 框架是指
by an agent learned to interact with its environment.
智能体学习如何与环境互动
We assume that time evolves and discrete timesteps.
我们假设时间会流逝并离散化时间步
At the initial timestep,
在一开始的时间步中
the agent observes the environment.
智能体会观察环境
You can think of this observation as
可以将这种观察结果看做
a situation that the environment presents to the agent.
环境呈现给智能体的情形
Then, it must select an appropriate action in response.
然后 它必须选择合适的响应动作
Then at the next timestep in response to the agents action,
在下一个时间步对智能体的动作做出响应时
the environment presents a new situation to the agent.
环境向智能体呈现新的情形
At the same time the environment gives the agent a reward which provides
同时环境向智能体提供一个奖励
some indication of whether the agent has responded appropriately to the environment.
作为回应，智能体必须选择一个动作 表示智能体是否对环境做出了正确的响应
Then the process continues where at each timestep
这一流程继续下去
the environment sends the agent an observation and reward.
在每个时间步 环境都向智能体发送一个观察结果和奖励
And in response, the agent must choose an action.
作为回应 智能体必须选择一个动作
In general, we don't need to assume that the environment
通常 我们不需要假设环境向智能体显示
shows the agent everything he needs to make well-informed decisions.
做出合理决策所需的一切信息
But it greatly simplifies the underlying mathematics if we do.
但如果我们如此假设 数学会大大简化
So in this course,
因此 在这门课程中
we'll make the assumption that the agent is able to
我们将假设智能体能够完全观察
fully observe what ever state the environment is in.
环境所处的任何状态
And instead of referring to the agent as receiving an observation,
此时 智能体接收的不再是观察结果
well, Huntsworth say that it receives the environment state.
而是环境状态
But let's make this description a bit clearer with
我们通过一些注释清晰地描述这一流程
some added notation where we again start from the very beginning at timestep zero.
从起始时间步 0 开始
The agent first receives the environment state which we denote by S0,
智能体首先接收环境状态 表示为 S0
where zero stands for a timestep zero of course.
0 表示时间步 0
Then, based on that observation the agent chooses an action,
然后 根据该观察结果 智能体选择一个动作 A0
A0, at the next timestep,
在下一个时间步
in this case, it timestep one and that's
即时间步 1
a direct consequence of the agent's choice of action, A0.
它是智能体所选动作 A0 的直接结果
And the environments previous state, S0,
环境的之前状态是 S0
the environment transitions to a new state, S1,
现在转换为新的状态 S1
and gives some reward,
并向智能体给出了
R1, to the agent.
一些奖励 R1
The agent then chooses an action, A1.
智能体然后选择一个动作 A1
At timestep two, the process continues where the environment passes the reward in state.
在时间步 2 这一流程继续 环境传递奖励和状态
Then the agent responds with an action and so on.
然后智能体做出动作响应 以此类推
Whereas the agent interacts with the environment,
当智能体与环境互动时
this interaction is manifest as a sequence of states, actions, and rewards.
这种互动表现为一系列的状态 动作和奖励
That said, the reward will always be the most relevant quantity to the agent.
但是 奖励将始终是与智能体最相关的数量
To be specific, any agent has the goal to maximize
具体而言 任何智能体的目标都是
expected cumulative reward or the some of the rewards attained over all timesteps.
最大化期望累积奖励或在所有时间步中获得的某些奖励
In other words, it seeks to find the strategy for choosing
换句话说 它旨在寻找一种
actions with the cumulative reward is likely to be quite high.
使累积奖励很有可能最高的动作选择策略
And the agent can only accomplish this by interacting with the environment.
智能体只有通过与环境互动 才能实现这一目标
This is because at every timestep,
因为在每个时间步
the environment decides how much reward the agent receives.
环境都决定智能体会接收多少奖励
In other words, the agent must play by the rules of the environment.
也就是说 智能体必须遵守环境规则
But through interaction, the agent can learn
但是通过互动 智能体能够学习这些规则
those rules and choose appropriate actions to accomplish its goal.
并选择合适的动作来实现它的目标
And this is essentially what we'll try to accomplish in this course.
这正是我们在这门课程中要学习的内容
But it's important to emphasize that all of this is
但是要强调的是
just a mathematical model for a real world problem.
所有这些只是现实问题的数学模型
So if you have a problem in mind that you
如果你想到了一个
think can be solved with reinforcement learning,
你认为可以用强化学习解决的问题
you will have to specify the states, actions,
你需要指定状态 动作和奖励
and rewards, and you'll have to decide the rules of the environment in this course.
并且需要制定环境规则
You'll see a lot of examples for how to accomplish this.
在这门课程中 你将见到很多如何实现这种流程的示例